Elias F. Gabriel

A passionate and hard working team player & engineer, I love working with others to solve complex problems with effective, creative and unique solutions. I'm dedicated to continually expanding my engineering experience to enrich, empower and elevate people, companies and communities.

6313 Liebig Ave Bronx NY, 10471 +1 (347) 579-9754 eliasfgabriel@gmail.com eliasfgabriel.com

EXPERIENCE

The Glass Files, Bronx NY — Co-Founder, Chief Software Engineer

June 2017 - PRESENT

Revisioned, rewrote, and supervised workflow and process documentation to ensure business continuity at The Glass Files, an ed-tech platform empowering students and their families to organize, share, and connect their stories with History. Designed and implemented new platform features, mobile applications, and improved suite-wide performance by 90%.

scenyc inc., Bronx NY — Director of Technology

December 2018 - PRESENT

Coordinated infrastructure, server, and software management while reconfiguring and migrating existing systems from a dedicated environment to the cloud (Amazon Web Services via Elastic Beanstalk, S3, EC2, and RDS). Upgraded the business management and information software suite (MAISTM) to a newer version of Ruby [on Rails]. Cut infrastructure costs by 70%.

Olin College of Engineering, Needham MA — N.I.N.J.A (Need it Now Just Ask)

August 2019 - December 2019

Teaching assistant for **Modeling and Simulation in the Physical World** (MTH1111). Provided individual support to help students understand covered material and apply it in projects using Python.

Riverdale Country School, Bronx NY — Technology and Media Consultant

June 2017 - July 2018

Created a utility to efficiently and automatically burn SRT-formatted subtitles into videos produced with Adobe Premiere. Self-taught the basics of Adobe After Effects and ExtendScript, as well as Adobe Premiere to assist in the editing and production of high-quality marketing videos for the school.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Olin College of Engineering, Needham MA

Bachelor of Science in Engineering with Computing, Class of 2022 GPA: 3.92

Coursework: Metals, Mining, and the Environment, Data Structures and Algorithms, Software Systems, Principles of Engineering, Quantitative Engineering Analysis, Complexity Science, Introduction to Sustainability

SKILLS

Extensive object-oriented programming, RUBY (ON RAILS), PYTHON, C++,so JAVASCRIPT, HTML, CSS, NODEJS, JAVA, *NIX, and server infrastructure and management

Creative problem-solving, collaborative leadership and project management

Conversational Spanish

Lifeguard - First Aid, CPR

Projects

Olin Aquatic Robotic
Systems (OARS) Electrical and Systems
Integration Lead:
Developing autonomous
aquatic research vessels
using satellite waypoint
navigation and integrated
software and sensor
systems.

Followbot: Lead a team to design, fabricate, wire, and program an autonomous walking human-seeking robot.

Parceler: Designed and developed a simple alternative to Rails' Webpack-based asset management system using ParcelJS to require almost no out-of-the-box setup (https://git.io/JeE3c).